http://www.credit.org/privacy-policy/

Options:
Credit Building
Get Free Credit CounselingWorking with a credit coach will help you pay off debt fast and manage your personal finances more efficiently. Our free credit advice is personalized to your unique situation.find out more
Monitor & Improve Your Credit ScoreThe details on your credit report, like your credit score, directly impact your everyday financial well-being. Your credit score influences your ability to secure the best interest rates on loans, helps you qualify for housing, rentals or a mortgage, and even plays a role in obtaining employment for certain types of positions.find out more
Review Your Credit ReportYour credit report can influence your ability to find housing, employment and secure a loan. Knowing your score and understanding your report are the first steps towards your financial health. Our certified financial coaches will guide you through your credit report, answer questions, and give personalized guidance towards improving your score.find out more
Free Online Budgeting ToolsCredit.org provides access to tools that allow you to pay off debt and access a financial goal planner. Use these FREE tools to break free from debt and take the first step toward achieving your financial goals.find out more
Debt Relief
Get Free Debt CounselingDebt is common and manageable. Our certified financial coaches are standing by ready to answer your questions, provide guidance, and help you reach your financial goals. Speaking to one of our certified debt coaches is completely free. Our coaches will be able to review all of your options for getting out of debt and guide you toward the best path forward.find out more
Debt Management Programs & PlansA financial coach will help you determine whether a Debt Management Plan is your best path toward effectively managing debt levels. Once you enroll in a plan, we become your personal advocates, working closely with you and your creditors to pay off debt in a timely fashion.find out more
Debt Settlement Solutions & ProgramsDebt settlement is a process that allows you to pay off debt by paying a single lump sum that is lower than the total amount you owe. Settlements are achieved through negotiation between lenders and consumers or a third-party debt settlement company. Our coaches will help you assess if debt settlement is the best debt resolution option for you.find out more
Filing for BankruptcyCredit.org is an Executive Office for United States Trustees ‘EOUST‘ approved agency. Our experienced financial coaches work with people in all stages of their financial life, including the challenging decision of bankruptcy. Our coaches can help you obtain the certificate you need to file for bankruptcy or discharge debts in bankruptcy.
find out more
Housing Assistance
Get First-Time Home Buyer CoachingOur award-winning coaches are here to help prepare you to own a home. We provide education, resources, and guidance to make your home buying process efficient, stress-free, and rewarding.find out more
Take Our Mortgage Readiness QuizHomeownership is more affordable than you may think. See how much home you can afford with our Mortgage Calculators and Mortgage Readiness Quiz.find out more
Foreclosure Help & Mortgage AssistanceWork with our HUD approved housing counselors who will assess your current mortgage needs and help guide you to the options that are best suited for your specific situation.find out more
Online Classes for First-Time Home BuyersDon’t start your home buying journey without getting the facts first! Whether you’re a first-time home buyer or someone looking to get back into home ownership, you will need a well laid plan. Our HUD-approved Home Buyer Classes will help you navigate the home buying process and equip you with useful tools & resources for purchasing a home.
find out more
Resources:
Education & Classes
Educational Articles
Financial Calculators
Get Started Now
1 (800) 431 – 8157
Options:
Credit Building
Get Free Credit CounselingWorking with a credit coach will help you pay off debt fast and manage your personal finances more efficiently. Our free credit advice is personalized to your unique situation.find out more
Monitor & Improve Your Credit ScoreThe details on your credit report, like your credit score, directly impact your everyday financial well-being. Your credit score influences your ability to secure the best interest rates on loans, helps you qualify for housing, rentals or a mortgage, and even plays a role in obtaining employment for certain types of positions.find out more
Review Your Credit ReportYour credit report can influence your ability to find housing, employment and secure a loan. Knowing your score and understanding your report are the first steps towards your financial health. Our certified financial coaches will guide you through your credit report, answer questions, and give personalized guidance towards improving your score.find out more
Free Online Budgeting ToolsCredit.org provides access to tools that allow you to pay off debt and access a financial goal planner. Use these FREE tools to break free from debt and take the first step toward achieving your financial goals.find out more
Debt Relief
Get Free Debt CounselingDebt is common and manageable. Our certified financial coaches are standing by ready to answer your questions, provide guidance, and help you reach your financial goals. Speaking to one of our certified debt coaches is completely free. Our coaches will be able to review all of your options for getting out of debt and guide you toward the best path forward.find out more
Debt Management Programs & PlansA financial coach will help you determine whether a Debt Management Plan is your best path toward effectively managing debt levels. Once you enroll in a plan, we become your personal advocates, working closely with you and your creditors to pay off debt in a timely fashion.find out more
Debt Settlement Solutions & ProgramsDebt settlement is a process that allows you to pay off debt by paying a single lump sum that is lower than the total amount you owe. Settlements are achieved through negotiation between lenders and consumers or a third-party debt settlement company. Our coaches will help you assess if debt settlement is the best debt resolution option for you.find out more
Filing for BankruptcyCredit.org is an Executive Office for United States Trustees ‘EOUST‘ approved agency. Our experienced financial coaches work with people in all stages of their financial life, including the challenging decision of bankruptcy. Our coaches can help you obtain the certificate you need to file for bankruptcy or discharge debts in bankruptcy.
find out more
Housing Assistance
Get First-Time Home Buyer CoachingOur award-winning coaches are here to help prepare you to own a home. We provide education, resources, and guidance to make your home buying process efficient, stress-free, and rewarding.find out more
Take Our Mortgage Readiness QuizHomeownership is more affordable than you may think. See how much home you can afford with our Mortgage Calculators and Mortgage Readiness Quiz.find out more
Foreclosure Help & Mortgage AssistanceWork with our HUD approved housing counselors who will assess your current mortgage needs and help guide you to the options that are best suited for your specific situation.find out more
Online Classes for First-Time Home BuyersDon’t start your home buying journey without getting the facts first! Whether you’re a first-time home buyer or someone looking to get back into home ownership, you will need a well laid plan. Our HUD-approved Home Buyer Classes will help you navigate the home buying process and equip you with useful tools & resources for purchasing a home.
find out more
Resources:
Education & Classes
Educational Articles
Financial Calculators
Consent and Privacy Policy
Consent
You are providing your express “written” consent to credit.org to contact you at the email and phone number provided (including by auto dialer, text and pre-recorded messaging) via landline and mobile device (including SMS and MMS) even if your phone number is currently listed on any state, federal or corporate Do Not Call list. Standard message and data rates may apply. Consent is not required as a condition to purchase any of our goods and services. If you would prefer to contact us rather than having us contact you, please call us at 1 (888) 845-0418.
Privacy Policy
Credit.org is committed to assuring the privacy of individuals and/or families who have contacted us for assistance.  Your privacy is held in strict confidence in compliance with the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Privacy Act except as authorized to be released by you. We assure you that all “nonpublic personal information” shared both orally and in writing such as your name, address, telephone number, assets, liabilities and any other personal information concerning your finances will be managed within legal and ethical considerations.
Privacy Fact Sheet ›
What personal information is collected from you, and how we use it. In general, credit.org uses the information collected on our web site to help us understand who uses our web site and how it is used, to perform statistical analysis of user behavior or to evaluate and improve our online services, and to personalize your online experience.  If you enter your email address, name and phone number, and ask for more information or send us an email with questions or comments, we may use your information to send you a welcoming email, electronic newsletters, contact you about services, information and news that may be of interest to you and provide you with targeted feedback, and may file your questions or comments for future reference. In addition, if you become a client of credit.org, we may use your information to send you an email with instructions on how to set up your account(s).
The web site also offers community boards, blogs, and chat rooms. You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.
We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. Children under the age of thirteen may not submit any personally identifiable information to credit.org.
How your information is transferred to Third Parties. The following privacy practices detail circumstances under which we may release your information to a third party as permitted by law:
When you have provided a request to do so, or when our staff has been served by a valid subpoena.
We may compile data and aggregate information that you give us, and share it with our partners, advertisers and connected sites, but this information may not be disclosed in a manner that would personally identify you in any way.
Access to nonpublic personal information about you may be released to contractors or agencies with legitimate authority to provide services to you, or to monitor credit.org’s practices for quality assurance or compliance purposes.
How to modify/delete your information. You may access or correct your personal information, privacy preferences and/or opt-out of communications by writing or calling credit.org at:
Credit.org
P O Box 5438
Riverside, CA 92517-5438
Phone: 1.800.947.3752
Fax: 1.951.781.8027
Please include your name, address, and/or e-mail address when you contact us.
Credit.org’s use of cookies and web beacons
What is a cookie?  We automatically track certain data based upon your behavior on our site using “cookies” and other devices like pixel tags. We use this information to do internal research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand our users. This data may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address. A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from our web server to your browser which is saved on the hard drive of your computer. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites, and it will not damage your system. You can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies, require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Blocking all cookies will affect your online experience and may prevent you from enjoying the full features offered by credit.org.  Whether you configure your web browser (Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer, Safari, etc.) to delete and/or control the use of cookies, or use the opt-out mechanism described below to manage cookies is at your discretion.
What type of cookies do we use and when? There are two broad classes of cookie: session and permanent. Session cookies are used to keep track of information needed by a user and their browser on their journey through a website. These cookies are used to recognize that you are logged into the website and help the website to remember your customized preferences.  For example, by saving your language preferences, we may be able to have our services appear in the language you prefer.  Session cookies have a short lifetime and expire within a few minutes of the user leaving the site. Credit.org uses session cookies to keep you logged in for the duration of your visit, which enables you to complete certain actions on the website. Credit.org uses permanent cookies to enable basic web traffic analysis using Google Analytics showing us which areas of the site are popular and those that are not often visited which allows us to prioritize our enhancements to our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site.  The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, and where visitors have come to the site and the pages they visited. We also use cookies and anonymous identifiers when you interact with services we offer to our partners, such as advertising services or features that may appear on other sites. When showing you tailored ads, we will not associate a cookie or anonymous identifier with sensitive categories, such as those based on race, religion, sexual orientation or health. Credit.org does use some cookies from trusted third party sources to enable us to provide you with certain features on our website, for example our live chat facility which is provided, uses cookies to enable the chat software to work.
Web Beacons.  We, our third party service providers, advertisers or our partners may also use “web beacons” or clear .gifs, or similar technologies, which are small pieces of code placed on a web page to monitor the behavior and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page. Web beacons may be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page. For example, if you often visit content on credit.org about debt relief, we may use web beacons to infer your possible interest in debt relief and may deliver an ad to you related to that interest.. The type of information collected might include the IP address of the computer, the web page being viewed, the date/time it was viewed, and user activity on the page. It’s important to understand that these technologies do not use personally identifiable information to make this happen but instead use anonymous identifiers within the cookies stored in your browser. We do not collect personally identifiable information through web beacons.
Use of your personal information submitted to other websites.  Some of our sites contain links to or integrations with other sites such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc., whose information practices may be different than ours.  We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites even if you accessed the third party website using links from our website or you linked to our website from a third party website. The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers and others is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.   We recommend that you check the policy of each website you visit and contact the owner or operator of such website if you have any concerns or questions.
Opt-out. If you do not wish to allow your browsing information on our sites to be aggregated and analyzed by us, you may choose to opt-out.  When you opt out, we will place an opt-out cookie on your computer to track that you’ve opted out. The opt-out cookie tells us not to use your information for delivering relevant online advertisements. That opt-out cookie (like all cookies) is associated with a particular computer and browser, so for example if you get a new computer, install a new browser, or delete your cookies, you’ll need to opt-out again.  If you opt out, you’ll still see the same ads from us online, but we just won’t know it’s you, so we won’t be able to apply any of your preferences to make them as relevant to you.
We understand that some users may choose to opt out of our interest-based ads.
You can opt-out via the Network Advertising Initiative industry at: www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp
You can opt-out via the Consumer Choice Page at: www.aboutads.info/choices
You can opt-out via the Google Ads Preference Manager at: www.google.com/ads/preferences
Users may opt back in using the following links:
www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp
www.aboutads.info/choices
www.google.com/ads/preferences
Your access to our websites should not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.  Please note that if your browser is set to block third party cookies, this feature may not operate or display properly.
Monitoring of Phone Calls. Credit.org may monitor and/or record out-bound and in-bound telephone calls for quality assurance purposes, where permissible by law. Any recording or information obtained from monitoring telephone calls is held in the same strict confidence as all the information we gather.
Privacy-Related Complaints. If you believe that credit.org has not complied with this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information, you may write credit.org at the address indicated above. In your letter, please describe in as much detail as possible the ways in which you believe that credit.org has not complied with this policy. We will investigate your concern promptly.
Last Revised: 01/10/2019
Information
Credit.org is NOT A LOAN COMPANY. WE DO NOT LOAN MONEY.
Credit.org is an independent nonprofit financial counseling agency and is not affiliated with any mortgage, lending or servicing provider. The content, links and resources in this site are presented for informational purposes only and should not be construed as legal or tax advice.
Consent and Privacy Policy
Copyright © credit.org.
Build Your Credit.Get Out of Debt.Own A Home.
One of our Financial Coaches will contact you to discuss the path to reaching your financial goals.
Get Started
Speak to a Coach Now 800.431.8157Hours of Operation Monday through Friday 7am to 7pm (Pacific)
